Oneida Community Collection
Oneida Community Collection
- Manuscripts and personal papers
  - Towner, James W., 1874-1909
    - Correspondence (Box 75)
      1877 Jl 22 to Tirzah C. Miller
      1878 My 31 to Charlotte M. Leonard
      Je 3 to Mary Louise Prindle
      Jl 11 to Mary Louise Prindle
      1879 Ja 26 to John Humphrey Noyes with his reply
      1893 O 25 to Frederick W. Frankland
      1909 Ag 5 to William A. Hinds
    - Writings (Box 75)
      Circular series on contracts
      "Essay on Community property" (Ap 22, 1874)
  - Towner, Martha Reeve, 1874-1879 (Box 75)
    Journal (typescript)
  - Tuttle, Frank W., 1870; 1875 (Box 75)
    1870 Mr 7 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1875 Ap 4 to Tirzah C. Miller
  - Underhill, Portia, 1869-1906; undated (Box 75)
    1869 F 21 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1871 O 1 to Beulah Hendee
    1873 O14 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1874 My 14 to Grovy
    1876 Jl 9 to Mary Louise Prindle
    Ag 7 to Beulah Hendee
    1877 Ja 21 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1880 Ap 25 to Charlotte
    1895 F to Grovie
    undated to John Humphrey Noyes
    [no year] 5 3 to Harriet
    [no year] 5 15 to Beulah Hendee
    1900-1906 File of family correspondence
  - Underwood, C. W., 1867-1884 (Box 75)
    See also 1865 description of visitor--(Box 16)
    1876 Jl 30 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1877 Jl 16 to Harriet N. Olds
    1884 Ap 11 to Tirzah C. Miller
  - Vaill, James S., 1871; 1882 (Box 75)
    1871 F 8 to James B. Herrick
    1882 Clipping re: arson trial
  - Van Velzer, 1894 (Box 75)
    F 5 from Judge G.A. Forbes re: Van Velzer case
  - Van Velzer, Lyman, 1856 (Box 75)
    Mr 10 to Marcus L. Worden
  - Van Velzer, Sarah, undated (Box 75)
  - Walbridge, Eliza Ann, 1873-1879 (Box 75)
    1873 Ag 22 to Uncle John
    1873-1879 File of letters to John L. Skinner
  - Warne, Henry, 1875-1914 (Box 75)
    1875 O 25 to Alfred Barron
    1901 F 9 to Portia Underhill Allen
    1914 Ja 15 Obituary from Utica Dailv Press
  - Waters, Hial, 1857; undated (Box 75)
    1857 Ja 14 to Marcus L. Worden
    [no year] 5 20 to Silas and Naomi Howard (copy; original in Amherst College Library)
  - Waters, Louisa T., undated (Box 75)
    to Beulah Hendee
  - Wayland-Smith, Francis, 1865-1899
    - Correspondence (Box 76)
      1865 My 24 to George E. Cragin
      Je 2 to George E. Cragin
      Je 27 to George E. Cragin
      1872 O 4 to Tirzah C. Miller
      1873 Ja 16 to Tirzah C. Miller
      Ja 26 to Tirzah C. Miller
      O 6 to Tirzah C. Miller
      1876 O 18 to Tirzah C. Miller
      D 2 to Tirzah C. Miller
      D 3 to Tirzah C. Miller
      D 12 to Tirzah C. Miller
      1879 F 27 to John Humphrey Noyes
      Je 27 to Mary
      1880 My 5 to Tirzah C. Miller
      N 26 to Tirzah C. Miller
      1893 F 23 to William A. Hinds
      Ag 29 to William A. Hinds
      1897 S 15 to F.W. Frankland
      1899 Ap 7 to William A. Hinds
    - Writings (Box 76)
      "What held the O.C. together"
      1877-1902 Diary (copy)
  - Wayland-Smith, Gerard, undated (Box 76)
    Mr 11 to Dorothy Barron
  - Wayland-Smith, Louis, 1955 (Box 76)
  - Whitfield, Elizabeth, 1867 (Box 76)
    Jl to Harriet N. Olds
  - Whiting, Flora, 1867-1878 (Box 76)
    1867 S 26 to Fanny M. Leonard
    O 6 to Fanny N. Leonard
    1869 Ja 16 to Fanny N. Leonard
    1876 Jl 3 to Fanny N. Leonard
    Jl 9 to Fanny M. Leonard
    Jl 28 to Fanny M. Leonard
    Ag 7 to Fanny M. Leonard
    1877 Mr 11 to Fanny N. Leonard
    1878 My 13 to Charlotte(?)
  - Woolworth, Arabelle, 1878 (Box 76)
    O 21 to Mary Louise Prindle
  - Woolworth, Emma C., undated (Box 76)
    [no year] S 15 to Mrs. Joslyn
    [no year] S 23 to Mrs. Joslyn
  - Woolworth, William H., 1867-1904; undated (Box 76)
    1871 Ap 27 to Howard family(?) (copy; original in Amherst College Library)
    Ag 15 to Naomi Howard (copy; original in Amherst College Library)
    1877 Je 21 to Theodore R. Noyes
    1878 Ap 7 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1879 My 3 to Mary Louise Prindle
    O 29 to James B. Herrick
    1881 Ag 28 to James B. Herrick
    1893 O 26 to William A. Hinds
    O 30 to William A. Hinds
    1894 O 13 to William A. Hinds
    D 5 to William A. Hinds
    1895 Ja 10 to William A. Hinds
    Ja 20 to William A. Hinds
    Ja 30 to William A. Hinds
    1896 Je 9 to William A. Hinds
    O 21 to Mrs. Inslee
    O 21 to William A. Hinds
    1897 Ja 22 to William A. Hinds
    Ap 12 to William A. Hinds
    1898 Je 19 to William A. Hinds
    Ja 21 to William A. Hinds
    1900 F 3 to William A. Hinds
    N 21 to William A. Hinds
    D 25 to William A. Hinds
    1901 Ja 27 to William A. Hinds
    Ag 27 to William A. Hinds
    N 25 to William A. Hinds
    1902 Ja 14 to William A. Hinds
    My 20 to William A. Hinds
    Je 29 to William A. Hinds
    1903 My 30 to William A. Hinds
    1904 Mr 12 to William A. Hinds
  - Worden, Cornelia, 1867-1870; undated
    - Correspondence (Box 76)
      1867 My 1 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1870 Je 19 to Charlotte N. Leonard
    - Writings (Box 76)
      1847-1864 Diary
      1851-1868 File of letters to Marcus L. Worden
      1878 Diary (copy)
      1909 Quadrangle article on trip to Putney
  - Worden, Harriet, 1852-1890; undated (Box 76)
    - Correspondence
      1852 F 24 to Marcus L. Worden-(with Harriet A. Noyes note)
      1855 O 4 to Marcus L. Worden
      1862 Ja 28 to John R. Miller
      1869 S 9 to Tirzah C. Miller
      S 14 to Harriet
      1871 O 28 to Harriet H. Skinner
      1876 Ja 26 to John Humphrey Noyes
      Jl 28 to Tirzah C. Miller
      O 8 to James W. Towner
      1890 F 3 to Stella
      [no year] O 28 to Tirzah C. Miller
      1851-1867 File of letters to Marcus L. Worden
    - Writings
      1868-1869 Diary--with unidentified mss.
  - Worden, John Sweating, 1854 (Box 76)
    F 7 to Marcus L. Worden
  - Worden, Leander W., 1848-1876 (Box 76)
  - Worden, Marquis (Marcus) de LaFayette, 1842-1890; undated (Box 77)
    1842 Ag 12 Receipt to Orvis Worden
    1849 Ag 29 to ?
    S 2 to ?
    S 9 notes on criticism of Mr. Ackley
    S 26 journal notes
    N 13 to Sister Jane
    D 5 notes
    D 29 to William H. Cook
    D 31 to George Cragin
    185- 3 letters from Catherine L.B. (typescripts) with miscellaneous undated and dated fragments of incoming correspondence.
    1850 Ja 27 to Mr. Abbott(?)
    Ap 28 to Harriet Worden
    S 11 to William H. Cook
    1851 Mr 18 to Sister Jane
    Mr 23 to Mr. Gibbs
    O 30 to ?
    N 12 to John Humphrey Noyes
    1852 F 10 Receipt for burial expenses for Marcus L. Worden's wife
    F 22 to Harriet Worden
    Mr 28 to Sister Hannah
    Mr 29 to Sister Hannah
    1853 Ap 28 to Mr. Hollister(?)
    Jl 31 to [sister?]
    S 1 to Brooklyn Friends
    S 1 to Brother Dean
    1854 My 9 to Brother Dean
    Jl 12 to Brother Holister
    Ag 13 to Harriet Worden
    D 21 composition
    1855 Mr 10 log entry
    Mr 11 log entry
    Mr 13 log entry
    Mr 28 log entry
    1857 O 15 to George Cragin
    1861 N 6 'My dear sister'
    N 19 'My dear sister'
    1862 F log entry
    1867 S 7 to ?
    D 7 log entry.
    D 9 log entry
    D 13 log entry
    D 27 log entry
    1869 Jl 15 account sheet
    1872 D 14 Treasury note
    1890 Jl 8 to Harriet Worden
    Undated correspondence
    Incoming correspondence
    Diary (1863)
    "Road Book" (1864-1869)
    Record of buildings (1868-1869)
  - Worden, Sophia, undated (Box 77)
    2 letters to Marcus L. Worden
  - Worden, Stella, 1904-1908; 1950 (Box 77)
    1904-1908 File of 12 letters to William A. Hinds
    1905-1907 File of letters to the Allen family
    1950 S.W. to Robert Wayland-Smith with his reply
  - Worden, Susan, 1851-1868 (Box 77)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence from various notables (Box 77)
    Includes letters from George Bernard Shaw, Wilkie Collins, Susan B. Anthony, Mildred Howells (copy) -- with drawing entitled 'Easter' Greetings (1891)
  - Anonymous letters and unidentified fragments (Box 77)
  - Spiritualism and specimens of automatic writing associated with seances (Box 77)
- Newspapers - received on exchange
  - Advocate and family guardian (N.Y.), 1876 (Oversize 3)
  - Banner of light (Boston), 1872 (Oversize 3)
  - Boston investigator, 1875-1876 (Oversize 3)
  - Broom's paper, 1880 (Oversize 3)
  - Chariot of wisdom and love (Portland, Me.), 1864 (Oversize 3)
  - Chicagoan, 1869 (Oversize 3)
    See also Miscellaneous (Oversize 5)
  - Christian union (London), 1880 (Oversize 3)
  - Cincinnati commercial extra (Oversize 3)
  - Communist (St. Louis), 1880 (Oversize 3)
  - Crucible (Baltimore), 1871 (Oversize 3)
  - Daily graphic (N.Y.), 1876 (Oversize 3)
  - Davis' battle-axe (Worcester), 1876-1877 (Oversize 3)
  - Divinity physician (Benton, Ohio), 1868 (Oversize 3)
  - Echoes of nature (Bath, Me.), 1871 (Oversize 3)
  - Eclectic & peacemaker (N.Y.), 1876-78 (Oversize 3)
  - Educational gazette (Philadelphia), 1870 (Oversize 3)
  - Era (Westminster, England), 1872 (Oversize 3)
  - Good time coming (Berlin Heights, Ohio), 1859 (Oversize 3)
  - Hacker's pleasure boat (Berlin, N.J.), 1867 (Oversize 3)
  - Hull's crucible (Boston), 1874-1877 (Oversize 3)
  - Kingdom of heaven (Boston), 1874 (Oversize 3)
  - Labor (N.Y.), 1877; See also Miscellaneous (Oversize 5) (Oversize 3)
  - Labor vindicator (New Martinsville, W.Va.), 1877 (Oversize 3)
  - National transition (Trenton, N.J.), 1872 (Oversize 3)
  - New campaign (Berlin Heights, Ohio), 1871 (Oversize 3)
  - New and divine government (Chicago), 1868 (Oversize 3)
  - New York herald, 1865 (Oversize 3)
  - Progressive communist (Kansas), 1875-1876 (Oversize 3)
  - Prometheus (N.Y.), 1877 (Oversize 3)
  - Public opinion (London), 1872 (Oversize 3)
  - Religio-philosophical journal (Chicago), 1869-1872 (Oversize 3)
  - Riverside health journal (Hamilton, Ill.), 1875 (Oversize 3)
  - Rural notes (Canonsburg, Pa.), 1877 (Oversize 3)
  - Saturday evening call (Jersey City), 1871 (Oversize 3)
  - Socialist (N.Y.), 1876 (Oversize 3)
  - Socialist (Sheffield, England), 1877 (Oversize 3)
  - Social-smasher (Berlin Heights, Ohio), 1871 (Oversize 3)
  - Spiritual Puritan (New Haven, Conn.), 1844 (Oversize 3)
  - Stumblingstone (Beloit, Wisc.), 1870 (Oversize 3)
  - Sun (Toledo, Ohio; N.Y.), 1875 (Oversize 4)
  - Theocratic Messenger (Barre, Maine), 1845 (Oversize 4)
  - Thoughts & events (N.Y.), 1880 (Oversize 4)
  - Toledo sun (Berlin Heights, Ohio), 1875 (Oversize 4)
  - Truthteller (Lake Constance, Minn.), 1877 (Oversize 4)
  - Universe (N.Y.), 1870 (Oversize 4)
  - Universe (Chicago), 1869 (Oversize 4)
  - Voice from spirit land, 1875? (Oversize 4)
  - Woman's journal (Boston), 1872 (Oversize 4)
  - Woman's truth teller (Utica, N.Y.), 1872 (Oversize 4)
  - Watchman's cry (Westminster, Conn.), 1872-1873 (Oversize 4)
  - West (San Francisco), 1873 (Oversize 4)
  - Woodhull & Claflin's weekly (N.Y.), 1874-1875 (Oversize 4)
  - Word (Princeton, Mass.), 1872-1877 (Oversize 4)
  - Worker (N.Y.), 1879 (Oversize 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 5)
- Maps
  - Home domain of the Oneida Community drawn from actual surveys by T.R. Noyes, 1864 F (Map-case 73)
  - Proposed branch of Midland R.R. between O.C. and W.P. From surveys by J. Abbott and J.J. Skinner., 1868 S (Map-case 73)
  - Buildings and southern grounds of Oneida Community drawn from topographical surveys. By J.J. Skinner. (original in KHC Coll.), 1869 S/O (Map-case 73)
  - Willow Place and foundry lot., 1869? (Map-case 73)
  - Section of the Oneida Community domain showing the location of a possible water privilege. From surveys by J.J. Skinner., 1872 Ag/S (Map-case 73)
  - Land belonging to the O.C. at Wallingford, Conn. Surveyed by P. Dignan., 1883? (Map-case 73)
  - Land belonging to the O.C. at Wallingford, Conn. Surveyed by P. Deignan., 1883 Ag (Map-case 73)
  - O.C. domain. Drawn by T.R.N., undated (Map-case 73)
- Realia
  - Short-dress costume (Oversize 6)